Contact

macubaque1@misena.edu.co www.linkedin.com/in/ marcocubaque (LinkedIn)

Main skills

Flask

Server Management

PL/SQL

Certifications

Scrum Fundamentals Certified(SFC)

Marco Antonio CubaquePorras

Developer -Database Administrator

Bogotá, Capital District, Colombia

Extract

Software Engineer with æolid base inAnalysis and Development of Information Systems, I specialize in the development and administration of databases. My experience alsocovers the development of cross-platform web-oriented applications.

In an ever-changing technologicalworld, I stayat theforefront of thelatest, safest and most reliable technologies.

My goal is to provide igh-quality solutions in any technological domain.

Experience

Attica- Industria Ambiental

Database administrator

November 2021 - April 2023 (1 year 6 months)

Madrid, Cundinamarca, Colombia

In my role as a database administrator, I led the implementation of technical standards and methodologies for data center design and management. My responsibilities included:

- •Design and administration of network technological infrastructure.
- •Risk management of informatioand technology solutions communications.
- •Implementation and control of theinformation security system.
- ·Supervision of personnel in charge.

Notable

achievements: •Successful implementation of anInformation Management and SecuritySystem: Idesigned comprehensivepolicies and protocols tomanage data efficiently and safely. Led the implementation of anadvanced technological solution that improved information accessibility, optimized operational efficiency, and strengthened regulatory compliance.

SyT Communicaciones

Database administrator

July 2020- September 2021 (Year 3 months)

Bogotá, Capital District, Colombia

At SyT Communications, Iplayed a key role in the development of computer applications and the integration of digital components. My Responsibilities included:

- •Design anddevelopment of computer applications.
- •Evaluation of computer application requirements.
- Computer application tests.
- •Implementation of computer applications.

Outstanding

achievements: •Comprehensive System Development! was responsiblefor conceiving, developing and run arobust customer management systemincluding centralized customer data management, alert generationand personalized notifications.

- •Improved Customer Experience: The implementation of this system allowed us to offer an improved customer experience by providing relevant information in real time that meets then eeds individual clients.
- •Increased Retention and oyalty: Significant increase incustomer retention and loyalty, improving overall customer satisfaction customer.
- •Process Automation: Automation of epetitive manual tasks resulting in greater operational efficiency and a greater ability toprovide faster and more accurate service tocustomers.

Education

Politecnico Grancolombiano

Degree in Engineering, Softwar&ngineering (October 2021 -December 2023)

Servicio Nacional De Aprendizaje SENA Technologist, Technology/Computer SoftwareTechnician (2017)